<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="alignment">
    <title>Alignment</title>
    <shortdesc/>
    <conbody>
        <p><b>What is it?</b></p>
        <p><i>Translation alignment</i> is a feature of most CAT tools, but its use can vary from
            very difficult (e.g. in Trados) to extremely easy. The alignment tool matches the source
            and target language files side-by-side, to determine which pairs belong together.</p>
        <p>You use it if you have the translated versions of your documents, but the translation
            wasn’t performed in a CAT tool so you don't have a translation memory. Now these
            documents need to be updated or changed across the languages and you want to retain the
            existing content, style and terminology. In addition, you wish to reduce costs, because
            there are a lot of repetitions and matches.</p>
        <p><image href="../images/Alignment.jpg" scale="50" id="image_jck_j2y_2tb"/></p>
        <p>TMSs are of great help here because this is a built-in feature. All you have to do is go
            to <i>TM </i>> <i>Align</i>, upload two documents (in source and target languages), run
            the alignment and analyse the results. In XTM you get an Excel file with texts in two
            columns and a probability score. </p>
        <p><image href="../images/Aligned%20docs.jpg" scale="60" id="image_chn_bhy_2tb"/></p>
        <p>You need to check it throughly and, if everything is done, upload the file in the <i>TM
                import</i> tab. Then, the translation memory is updated automatically.</p>
        <p>The only disadvantage is that the Align feature in XTM is shared with all of the
            customers on the cloud so sometimes it takes a long time for the file to be returned. It
            also takes longer oif you build the dictionary for a new language pair.</p>
    </conbody>
</concept>
